lubrizol.com 2019-08-20

# Lubrizol Privacy and Cookie Policy - Lubrizol

The Lubrizol Corporation and its affiliates (collectively "Lubrizol") respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal information that you may provide while using our websites. This policy describes the ways that information about our website visitors is collected, how that information is used, and how someone can request changes to the way their personal information is used or shared.

## Anonymous Information 

Anonymous information is unidentified information and is not associated with an individual. 

We may use anonymous cookies (See Cookies) to collect demographic information, track site metrics, or provide a richer experience for site visitors. Anonymous cookies do not contain any personally identifiable information. 

## Personally Identifiable Information 

Personally identifiable information (PII) is information that can identify you, such as your name, email address, address, and telephone number. 

We collect PII that you choose to provide to us when you register for access to a secure website; register for email newsletters; participate in surveys; request samples; request literature not on the site; or complete inquiry forms. When you provide this information to us, you are no longer anonymous for that activity. 

## How We Use Your Personally Identifiable Information

We make every effort to let you know before we collect PII via our websites. If you choose to provide PII via our websites, we want you know how we may use such information. We may use PII to:

  * provide you with product information 
  * allow you to purchase products 
  * market products to you 
  * send you email notices or newsletters at your request* 
  * communicate with you for other purposes

_*All email messages you receive from us will allow you to opt out of future emails._ __

## How We Keep Your Information Secure 

We are committed to protect personally identifiable information that you provide to us. Lubrizol does not intend to sell or otherwise disseminate your   
personally identifiable information to third parties without your permission. 

We use reasonable precautions to protect personally identifiable information, including technical, administrative, and physical procedures. 

In the event of a data breach, a notification will appear on the website within 72 hours of the breach.

When we contract with other companies to provide us with web services, we only share personally identifiable information with those that we believe share our commitment to privacy and information security. However, we are not responsible for any breach of security or for the actions of these parties and your use of the site is subject to Lubrizol’s Terms of Use. 

Lubrizol is not responsible for the information you volunteer about yourself in posting comments, discussion forums or other publicly accessible interactions. 

## Cookies 

To enhance your experience on our websites, many of our sites use cookies. A cookie (also known as a web cookie or browser cookie) is a string of coded text that is stored on a website visitor’s computer. Cookies alone do not provide personally identifiable information. If you choose to provide us with personally identifiable information, cookies may be used to store this information. Cookies can only be used by the server that gave them to you. 

Cookies can save you time as they help us remember who you are. Cookies allow us to be more efficient and help us to provide content that is important to you. 

We may use cookies for:

  * authentication (login) to a site
  * remembering your preferences when you return to the site 
  * storing selected items as you navigate through the site 
  * displaying relevant content to match your interest 
  * tracking site activity 
  * maintaining data for you as you navigate through our site

You do not need to accept cookies to visit our sites, but without them, your access to some areas and functionality may be limited or completely restricted. You can prevent the setting of cookies by adjusting the settings on your browser (see your browser Help for how to do this). 

### Cookies Used on This Site

**  Name** |   **Lifespan** |   **Purpose  **  
---|---|---  
_  **First-Party Cookies**_ |   |    
 SC_ANALYTICS_GLOBAL_COOKIE |  10 yrs |  Identifies repeat visits by unique visitors  
 ASP.NET_SessionId |  session |  Maintains an anonymized visitor session by the server  
 EL_PREF |  16 mos |  Remembers the language selected for future visits  
 CONSENT |  1 yr |  Stores a value so that we know if you have accepted cookies on this website  
  |   |    
  ** _Third-Party Cookies_** |   |    
 _ga |  2 yrs |  Used by Google Analytics to distinguish unique visitors by assigning a randomly generated number as a client identifier to calculate visitor, session and campaign data for the sites analytics reports  
 _gid |  1 day |  Used by Google Analytics to store and update a unique value for each page visited  
 __utmz |  6 mos |  Used by Google Analytics to identify the source of traffic to the site   
 __utma | 2 yrs |  Used by Google Analytics to distinguish between visitors and sessions to calculate new and returning visitor statistics  
 VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE |  6 mos |  Used by YouTube to measure your bandwidth to determine whether you get the new player interface or the old  
 YSC |  session |  Used by YouTube to help track the number of views for a particular video  
 PREF |  2 yrs |  Used by YouTube to help advertisers target preferences and serve up related content within an embedded YouTube video  
  |   |    
  ** _Recruitment Site Cookies_** |   |    
 RMK0 | session  |  Contains visitor's encrypted e-mail address to eliminate the need to re-enter their email as they navigate  
 RMK1 |  session  |  Used to identify a visitor during an apply action and provides security during an edit action  
 RMK4 |  session  |  Indicates if the visitor has acknowledged the "cookies policy" banner  
 RMK12 |  session  |  Used to simplify the workflow by auto-populating the email address in the subscribe box for future site visits  
 JSESSIONID |  session  |  Used to identify new visitors for tracking and analytics  
  
## How to Reach Us 

Upon request, Lubrizol will allow you to review, update, and/or remove personally identifiable information that you provided to us from this website. Please complete the Data Privacy Request Form, including your name, email address, country, and the nature of the request.

Removal of personally identifiable information will prevent you from accessing restricted content and sites (example: ([www.mylubrizol.com](https://www.mylubrizol.com/)) unless you re-enter your personally identifiable information at a later date. 

To be removed from a Lubrizol email list, please use the opt-out link on the email. 

Lubrizol websites may contain links to third party sites that Lubrizol does not own or maintain. Lubrizol is not responsible for the privacy practices or other aspects of those sites.
